<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Math2001&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://math2001.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Math2001&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Mathieu Paturel 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 07:51:15 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://math2001.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Find</title>
      <link>https://math2001.github.io/post/bash-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 07:51:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://math2001.github.io/post/bash-find/</guid>
      <description>The find command in bash is quite powerful, and knowing the basics might save you some scripting.
What does it do? It &amp;ldquo;finds&amp;rdquo; files. By default, it outputs their path relative to where you ran find. But, in addition of providing you with advanced &amp;ldquo;filters&amp;rdquo; it actually allows you to run commands on each of those files.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
The basics With this structure:
. ├── app │ ├── index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a hugo site on GitHub pages</title>
      <link>https://math2001.github.io/post/hugo-deploying-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 11:23:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://math2001.github.io/post/hugo-deploying-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>When you want to deploy a static website built with the fantastic Hugo on GitHub pages, you don&amp;rsquo;t have 100 of possibilities. A clean one, and an easy one 😄.
The easy one is to build your website to the docs folder. It&amp;rsquo;s not super clean though since the source code is on the same branch as the built code. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make diffing super great, gives a long output when you commit, you have to build at every single commit to keep consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Zen</title>
      <link>https://math2001.github.io/post/my-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:18:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://math2001.github.io/post/my-zen/</guid>
      <description>Python is by far my favorite language (I even wish we spoke it 😄).
One thing I found funny about it, and in the same time really good, is its zen.
They&amp;rsquo;re basically guidelines.
So, today, dans un élan d&amp;rsquo;inspiration, I decided to write my own. Here it is:
Keep it simple. Lazyness is a quality. Learn to use your tools efficiently. Get inspired by great things. Do one thing, and do it well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new blog</title>
      <link>https://math2001.github.io/post/my-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 19:43:23 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://math2001.github.io/post/my-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone!
My name&amp;rsquo;s Mathieu Paturel - @math2001 - and I love coding.
I&amp;rsquo;m French (from Provence, if you know where that is), but my family and I moved 2 years ago to Australia so that we could learn to speak fluently English (without this disgusting accent 😄).
How did I discovered coding It all started with the basic &amp;ldquo;programming language&amp;rdquo; (notice the quotes 😄). My farther taught me the very basic of programming (and it was pretty much all you could do with this language I&amp;rsquo;d 😆).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>